CONTACT ME AT

- Residence: Q.No.124-A,Sarwal Colony, Jammu, J&K
- divyangi.mahajan@yahoo.com
- +91 7780989702
- in www.linkedin.com/in/divyangi-mahajan
- https://github.com/divyangi-mhjn/
- https://divyangi-mhjn.github.io/myportfolio/

TECHNOLOGIES

React JS

Redux

Javascript

Node.js

PostgreSQL

Oracle Database

Herokı

AWS Services

knex.js

Java

SKILLS SUMMARY

Team Building

DevOps Proficiency

Solution Mockups

Agile

DIVYANGI MAHAJAN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

Tech-savvy developer with 3+ years of experience for collaborating and working on multiple web-based projects. Passionate, hardworking coder with penchant for developing customized interfaces that factor in unique demands for accessibility, reachability and security. Organized approach to meeting multiple, concurrent deadlines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES | MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

- Utilized technologies like React, Redux, Node.js ,PostgresSql, Javascript, AWS Services, Openshift Platform to develop new applications using agile methodologies.
- Participated in design and planning exercises for future software rollouts.
- Resolved system test and validation problems to provide normal program functioning.
- Played major role in layout modifications to improve the functionality.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence.

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

SKILL LOTTO SOLUTIONS | JUN 2018 - FEB 2019

- Developed and evolved consumer-facing, multi-channel roadmap for desktop, mobile and mobile web applications.
- Worked closely with other team members in tasks such as troubleshooting and debugging.
- Provided code maintenance and system upgrades to maximize performance.
- Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within production environment.

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

GEETA ENGINEERING COLLEGE| KURUKSHETRA UNIV.

Bachelor's In Computer Sciences | Aug 2014 - June 2018

• Received an honors degree with 79%

PROJECTS HIGHLIGHTS

Integrated Risk Assessment

July 2021 - Present

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, PostgreSql

Hosting Platform: Heroku

• This application is used to create assessment by admin for various quarters in a year which has to be filled in the the chosen receipients.

Password Reset Utility

Feb 2021 - June 2021

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, Oracle DB

Hosting Platform : Openshift

• The application is used to reset password for the selected oracle db instance for the selected user.

• The password is temporary and received through email.

CIO Awards Application

Oct 2020 - Feb 2021

Technologies : Node.js , ReactJs, Redux, knex.js, postgresSQL, Contentful

Hosting Platform: AWS

• A web application designed to streamline selection process for various awards given to selected projects that have been nominated and accepted .

• The forms filledby the nominee included features like autosave, ruch text editors for better user experience.

SmartdevOps Portal

April 2020 - Sep 2020

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, postgresSQL,Contentful

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- The web application is used to submit new proposals and manage theproposals that are ipresent in the system where different levels of status are present.
- Subscription of proposals for regular updates is also present.

DIA Assessment Tool

Oct 2019 - Mar 2020

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, postgresSQL, Contentful

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- The web application consists of dynamic question and answers portal where users have to answer some set of questions for the admin to evaluate.
- The questions are categorized on the basis of the different groups a user belongs to.

MIND Application

April 2019-Oct 2019

Technologies: Node.js, ReactJs, Redux, postgresSQL, Contentful, Denodo

Hosting Platform: Heroku

- This web application is an inventory system for company's internal data and classified information.
- Performance improvement algorithms were used.

Rajshree Lotteries

June 2018 - Feb 2019

Technologies: React Js, PHP, MySQL

- This web application used to deal with the information of accounts and the lotteries a user has bought and distributed further.
- The application displays and saves excel and pdf reports generated in the application